hey everyone Pastor Myers here just want
to invite you to check out this very
powerful message called the sealing
message uh speaking about Revelation
chap 12 the cealing of God's people and
how that connects with the message of
justification by faith so check this out
you're going to be
blessed
[Music]
amen amen Saints we are ready to get
into the word of God today put a one in
the chat if you are
prepared uh to hear what the Lord has to
say uh we're going to go ahead and open
up with prayer as I speak on this
subject
entitled the cealing message the sealing
message pray with me please Heavenly
Father we ask in a special way that your
word will be magnified today Lord that
we will understand the role
of the word and of the spirit in our
walk with you so L now Lord we pray that
you would bless us to this end May those
that are
watching be
moved to serve you with everything that
they have we pray this in Jesus name
amen and amen I want to invite you to
turn to come with me in the
screen uh to Revelation 7:1 again and we
are speaking today on the subject of the
ceiling message the ceiling message in
Revelation
7 and verse one the Bible reads after
these things I saw four Angels standing
on the four corners of the Earth holding
the Four Winds of the earth that the
wind should not blow on the earth nor on
the sea nor on any tree and I saw
another Angel a ascending from the East
having the Seal of the Living God and he
cried with a loud voice to the four
angels to whom it was given to hurt the
earth and the Sea
saying hurt not the
Earth neither the sea nor the
trees till we have sealed the Servants
of our God in their
foreheads we know that according to
revelation
chapter 7 the bible describes a ceiling
of the people of God that prepares them
to enter the kingdom of heaven and there
have been many sermons on this theme of
the
ceiling and yes today is going to be
another sermon but by the grace of God
we're going to see something that you
may have missed before that is going to
Enlighten you on the importance of this
sealing message found in Revelation chap
7 and so we're going to go on a journey
today and we're going to begin uh with
the Book of John we're going to kind of
go back to the very beginning of
creation and I want you to notice with
me in the Book of John chapter 1
beginning with verse one the Bible says
in the beginning was the
word and the word was with God and the
Word was God what I want to point out
here is the Greek word for word which is
logos uh something said including the
thought or including the thought by
implication of a topic uh also reasoning
mental faculty or motive by extension a
computation
our English word logic from
logic in other words it's as if the word
of God was given to us to
speak about or to speak to
logic now um here's what I'm going to
say you guys I see I see in the chat
that you're saying that it is uh the
sound is
choppy um
we are recording this and we're going to
upload a a clean copy so if the sound is
choppy just I'm going to ask that you
bear with me and just stick with me okay
uh we'll we'll we're going to upload a
clear copy a clean copy uh that will not
have any of these sound issues that
we're having today all right so put one
in the chat if you're good with
that um and I'm going to continue on
logos is the word from which we get the
word logic
from the word of God is designed to
speak to our logic our thinking
logos
logic thinking
okay um um let's go ahead and go back to
Genesis chapter 1 where we find the same
instance being spoken of but now again
in Genesis it says in the beginning God
created the Heaven and the Earth and the
Earth was without was without form and
void and darkness was upon the face of
the deep and the spirit of God moved on
the face of the waters the spirit of God
moved upon the face of the waters now
what I want to focus on here is the
spirit which is the Hebrew word ruach
meaning wind and I want you to
understand that the Bible says the
spirit of God moved upon the face of the
waters the Hebrew word rockov which
means to be relaxed to flutter to move
to shake now come back with me for a
moment the the the the the logos in the
beginning you have the logos which is
the word of God and you have the spirit
which is the ruok the wind now we just
saw that the word logos points to logic
the word of God is designed to reason
with us someone said yes ran come now
let us what reason
together but the
spirit serves a different
function the spirit in Genesis 1 moved
upon the face of the waters now why is
that significant we're going to go to
the New Testament and I want to show you
several times that the word moved is
used in the new Testament so let's go
Matthew chap 21 notice what the Bible
says and when he was coming to Jerusalem
all the city was moved saying who is
this
okay so what is this word signify here
when all the city was moved saying who
is this what does it signify what what
picture comes to your mind when you read
that the whole city was moved saying who
is this let me see what you have in the
chat what do you think what do you think
of when you hear the city was
moved I'm waiting are e either y'all are
still thinking or either you don't know
you're not sure what comes to mind when
you read that the city was
moved asking who is this all right so
Michelle says shaking up Patty says
wandering uh um come on guys if if if
something happens to you and you are
moved by it what what does that mean
inspired very good uh um amazed excited
yeah yeah yeah H uh all of these are
compelled Sarah all of these seem to
point to
emotion emotion when something happens a
and you're moved by that thing it's like
it reached down into your soul you were
moved you were you were compelled uh uh
you you you were filled with emotion you
were impressed you were excited so so
with that check this out
y'all
um notice with me several verses here
Matthew chapter
9:36 but but when he saw the multitudes
he was moved moved with
what
compassion compassion how about this uh
uh uh Matthew 20:4 and the 10 heard it
and when the 10 heard it they were
moved with indignation against their
Brethren how about this and when Jesus
was and when he was coming to Jerusalem
all the city was moved we had that text
earlier how about this one but the chief
priest moved the people that they should
rather release Barabas unto them uh Acts
7:9 and the Patriarchs moved with Envy
uh uh acts 21:30 and all the city was
moved and the people ran together and
they took Paul and Drew him out of the
temple forth with and shut the door
because they're trying to Stone Paul
remember they were moved with anger uh
Hebrews 11:7 uh speaking of Noah how he
was moved with fear okay come back with
me for a
moment if the word speaks to our logic
logos then the the work of the spirit
which is to
move must deal specifically with our e
Dash
motions okay please put a one in the
chat if you follow what we have just
laid out so
far the word of God speaks to our logic
but the spirit has something to do with
moving us with our
emotions I like how Rose puts that
somehow another the spirit is to
emotionally affect us affect us or
emotionally impact
us I want you to notice with me notice
with me Isaiah 55 verse 8 the Bible says
here for my thoughts are not your
thoughts
my thoughts are not your thoughts my
Logos my reasoning is not your
reasoning neither are your
ways my ways say the Lord for as the
heaven Heavens are higher than the earth
so are my ways higher than your ways and
my thoughts higher than your thoughts so
let's come back for a moment and I want
you to notice that there are two things
that are pointed out here there are uh
my thoughts are not your thoughts and my
ways are not your ways now we've already
identified that the logos was designed
to speak to our thoughts because God's
logos is way better than our
logos
yes all right amen so far so good so
what about these ways what is a way it's
a path it's a direction I'll check this
out according to Psalm 32:8 the Bible
says I will teach thee and instruct thee
in the
what in the
way that thou shalt go I will guide thee
with my eye now why is this verse
interesting in light of what we're
saying because the Bible tells us in
John 16:13 how be when the spirit of
Truth is come he will guide you into all
truth did y'all catch
that so so so he says here in Psalm 32 I
will teach thee and instruct thee in the
way that thou shalt go I will guide the
with my eye but it is the spirit's job
to guide into the
way to guide us into the way and in fact
in Revelation 5:6 we see here notice
this and I beheld in low in the midst of
the throne and of the four beasts and in
the midst of the elders stood a lamb as
it had been slain having seven horns and
seven eyes which are the seven spirits
of God sent forth into all the Earth so
then please note with
me that if the word of God is designed
to lead
us to to to speak to our logic logos
logic my thoughts are higher than your
thoughts then the spirit of God is
designed to guide us in the way
to show us the way to lead us into all
truth and this has something to do with
our
emotions
logos thoughts the spirit moves
us just as the spirit moved upon the
face of the waters so I want you to
check out we're we're building up
platform here and I want you to
understand something very important
because you
see character is made up of two
things character is made up of two
things what is it made up of character
is made up of the
thoughts logos and the
feelings
Spirit could it be that the logos and
the spirit have combined to work on on
the transformation of our character by
affecting the way that we think and the
way that we feel what do y'all think put
a one in the chat if y'all are follow me
so
far now now I we're going to focus today
specifically on the
spirit and we're dealing with the with
the sealing message here but I need you
to check this out because in Romans
chapter 8:1 16 the Bible says the spirit
itself beareth witness with our spirit
that we are the children of God is that
good news you
guys the work of the spirit is that it
Bears witness with our spirit so watch
this logos
logic my thoughts are not your thoughts
the spirit is given to to Bear witness
to our spirit logos thoughts spirit
Spirit are you with me are you following
so then so then uh the spirit the work
of the spirit is to give us confidence
that we're the children of
God put a one in the chat you're
following this this is crucial the work
of the spirit gives us the Assurance it
Bears witness with our spirit that we
are the children of God so for example
in in Matthew 3:1 16 you will note the
Bible says and Jesus when he was
baptized went up a straightway out of
the water and
lo the heavens were opened unto him and
he saw the spirit of God descending like
a dove and lighting upon him and lo a
voice a word a log on CR from Heaven
saying this is my beloved Son in whom I
am well pleased I want you to catch the
formula here Watch What
Happens the the the
spirit is present to Bear witness to the
fact that Jesus was the Son of God the
spirit was there spirit says I saw it I
heard the voice this is my beloved Son
in whom I am well pleased the work of
the spirit is to Bear
witness that we are the children of God
and we see that in the very baptism of
Jesus Christ the spirit was there to
Bear witness to the logos which was
spoken which was this is my beloved Son
in whom I'm well pleased now remember
remember in John 16:13 the Bible says of
the spirit for he shall not speak of
himself but whatsoever he hear
uh let me read that again for he shall
not speak of himself but whatsoever he
shall hear that shall he speak and he
will show you things to come so the work
of the spirit is not to speak his own
words but to speak what he
hears the work of the spirit is to speak
what he hears it is to move watch this
watch this what this is beautiful you
guys check this out second Peter 1: 21
how does the spirit speak what he hears
here here's how it is for the prophecy
came not in Old Time by the will of man
but the holy men of God spake as they
were what
everyone moved say that word again with
me ready 1 two 3
moved by the Holy
Ghost the work of the Holy Ghost is to
move the work of the Holy Ghost is to
move move God's people and here we see
that the Holy Ghost listens and then
speaks and he speaks through the
prophet's meaning then that the word of
God that is being that we have before us
is
being when you read something in the
word of God that is the spirit speaking
what he has
heard yes yes yes yes yes yes so then we
just need to go look at a couple verses
to say hey what is the spirit saying
what has the spirit said well check this
out this may blow your mind y'all here's
what the spirit said through
Paul for as many as are led by the
spirit of God they are the sons of
God all right
y'all how many of you can say that the
spirit of God has led
you the spirit of God has been leading
you when you accepted Christ into your
life and you said I want to follow the
leading of the spirit if the spirit of
God is leading you then the spirit says
that you are a son of
God the spirit
testifies you are can you all say Amen
you're a Son of God you are a daughter
of God how about this what else does the
spirit say Galatians 46 and because you
are Sons wait wait wait what I'm a son I
am
a Son of
God yes the spirit said so if you will
accept this if you will accept the
testimony of the spirit then you are a
son of
God because you are Sons God has sent
forth his Spirit of his son into your
hearts crying ABA father how about this
1 John 3:1 behold what manner of love
the father has bestowed that we upon us
that we should be called the Sons of God
therefore the world knoweth us not
because it knew him not verse two
beloved now are we the sons of God and
it does not yet appear what we shall be
but we know that when he shall appear we
shall be like him for we shall see him
as he is beloved we are according to the
spirit the sons of God the Bible says
but as many as received him to them gave
he power to become the sons of God even
to them that believe on his name now if
if y'all are with me so far just give me
a nice Amen in the chat give me a seven
in the chat if you're with me so far so
far we have learned that the logos the
word of God the doctrin of of the Bible
are given to speak to us
intellectually but the spirit was given
to move us to to to move us emotionally
so that we get this sense this feeling
that we are the children of God and the
way the spirit testifies watch this the
way the spirit testifies listen to me is
not by giving us a
fe by giving us a feeling that we're the
sons of God the way the spirit testifies
is by simply pointing to the
text and saying
the text says you're a Son of
God but I don't feel
like the text
says the text
says that you are a son of
God that you are a daughter of God the
logos because my job as a spirit is to
simply speak what I've heard it is to
point it is to glorify Christ so I'm
just telling you I don't really care
what you
feel I'm just telling you that the text
says that you are a son of
God now this is why this becomes crucial
beloved because if you go with me to
Ephesians chapter 4:30 listen to what
the Bible says and grieve not the holy
spirit of God whereby you are what
whereby you are what come on y'all come
on come on whereby you are sealed unto
the day of
redemption now what is the text telling
us
here the text is telling us that the
work of the holy spirit is is to seal
us now when something is
sealed it cannot be tampered with it
cannot be
moved when something is sealed it cannot
be moved it cannot be tampered with and
so what I want you to get here beloved
is that the the the the first work of
the spirit is to move us into the grace
of God but once we have been moved into
the grace of God then the work of the
spirit is to seal us so that we cannot
be moved out of the grace of God are
y'all with
me so the Bible says the Bible calls it
a cealing grieve not the spirit of God
in other words if the spirit tells you
if the spirit points to the word and
says you are Son of God you are accepted
of Christ you grieve the Spirit by
saying no but I don't feel like I've
been accepted I don't feel like God
loves me I don't feel like God God cares
what you're doing then is you're
grieving the spirit and the spirit will
say listen I don't care what you feel
look at the
text the text says you're a Son of God I
need you to trust the text I need you to
trust the logos
see see this is why Colossians 1:23 says
this if you
continue in the faith look look
watch if you continue in the faith
grounded and settled grounded and
settled and be not moved
away from the hope of the Gospel which
you have heard and which was preached to
every creature which is under Heaven
whereof I Paul and made a minister the
Bible says that we are to be grounded
and settled now when something is sealed
it's a settling into it's like I'm I've
settled in and nothing can move me away
from this position so the Bible says
here that we ought not to be moved away
the work of the spirit is never to move
us away from Christ but to move us
towards Christ and once it moves us in
into Christ then it wants to seal us in
Christ yes yes yes yes are y'all
following the holy spirit is designed to
move us into the
truth and then seal Us in that truth
watch this mentally and
emotionally just just as
soon just as soon we'll put this up on
the
screen just as soon as the people of God
are sealed in their foreheads it is not
any seal or Mark that can be seen but a
settling into the truth both
intellectually and
spiritually both
logos and spirit
both word and spirit both intellect and
emotionally so they cannot be
moved just as soon as God's people are
sealed and prepared for the shaking it
will come indeed it has already begun I
need y'all to catch this I need you to
understand what I'm saying here because
you see Satan is really only coming
after you in one way and it is the same
way in which he came after Jesus in
Matthew 4:1 the Bible says then was
Jesus led up of the spirit Into the
Wilderness to be tempted of the devil
and when he had fasted 40 days and 40
nights he was afterward hungry and the
tempter came to him and said if thou be
the Son of God all right
y'all do you remember do you remember
that when Jesus was baptized at the
Jordan come back with me come back to
the screen when Jesus was baptized at
the
Jordan the
spirit
testified that he was a Son of
God come on y'all put a one in the chat
if you're following what I'm saying
right now the spirit said let's come
back to come back come back to the
screen the spirit
said this is the Son of
God uh it it testified it heard the
voice from the father this is the Son of
God now what does Satan come to Jesus
with in the
wilderness if you be the Son of
God if you are a son of God I need you
to understand beloved that it is the
same thing that he does to us to this
day oh you're born again oh you're a
Believer if you are Son of God if you
are a son of God but he doesn't
say son of God why is nothing going
right for
you if you are a son of God how come
your prayer wasn't answered if you are a
son of God how come you stumbled
yesterday if you are a son of God how
come you made this mistake if you are a
son of God come on are you really a Son
of God and so what he wants to do he
wants you to try to prove that you're a
Son of God prove that you're a Son of
God so here's my question how do you
prove that you're a Son of God let's put
it in the chat let me see your answers
how do you prove that you're a Son of
God how do you prove what is one of the
best ways that you can prove that you're
a son of
God
listen
y'all it's already been
proven there is nothing for you to prove
because there's nothing that you can do
to prove you're a Son of God your Works
don't prove you're a Son of
God did you catch that your proof that
you are son of God is in the text so in
the same way Jesus responded it is
written when the Devil comes to you and
says man you're not really a Son of God
you're not really a daughter of God how
can you prove and there's the thing
beloved so many of us live our Christian
lives trying to prove that we're a Son
of God see I don't do this and I do this
and this is proof that I'm no no no no
the proof that you are a son of God is
in the text that you have accepted by
faith
fath that's the
proof so when the Devil comes to you and
says man are you really a Son of God
point to the text you tell them I
believe this
text now I know I know
listen just as the spirit in the in in
Jesus
pointed to the logo saying this is my
beloved Son in whom I'm well pleased you
beloved have to understand that when the
Devil comes to you saying you're not
really a child of God you're not really
a Son of God you're not really a
daughter of God point to the text
regardless of what you feel why because
the Bible tells us in Jeremiah 17:9
listen what it says the heart is
deceitful above all things and
desperately wicked who can know it the
text is telling us Jeremiah 179 don't
trust your
heart your heart may tell you H I'm not
a child of God but the but the spirit
says if you accept the text if you
accept what Jesus did for you then you
are a child of God now watch this watch
this watch it the spirit points us away
from our
emotions the spirit put the spirit says
no we're going to override your emotions
I need you to understand that your
salvation is not based in your emotion
your salvation is based in what the text
says it is
written now watch what happens when you
accept it is written when you accept the
testimony of the spirit the
result the
result is the fruit of the the Spirit
come on y'all come on look at the text
but the fruit of the spirit in other
words the fruit of accepting the
testimony of the spirit in your life now
becomes what love joy peace
longsuffering gentleness goodness Faith
meekness Temperance in other words your
emotions begin to fall in line with what
the word of God says now that you
understand that the word of God has
declared you as such now you begin to
feel these emotions of love and joy and
peace and longsuffering and gentleness
and goodness and Faith you see Beloved
the reason why so many of us are not
experiencing that love joy peace
longsuffering gentle goodness faith is
because we have not yet accepted the
testimony of the
spirit we have not yet accepted the
testimony of the spirit and saying
listen I know you don't believe it and I
know you feel like you're unworthy but
but Jesus died on the cross to make you
a Son of God now if you believe
it despite of what you
feel you will begin to feel according to
what you
believe man you mean you mean I'm a Son
of God yeah and now whoa I'm pretty
happy today you know what I'm pretty
excited
today I I'm doing good today why because
the text says forget about what my heart
felt yesterday the text says that I'm a
Child of God you see when the spirit of
God when you accept the work of the
spirit in in
in spirit from me restore unto me the
joy The Joy the joy of thy salvation and
uphold me with thy free spirit you see
Beloved the spirit points us to the work
of Christ that he did on our behalf come
on let me blow your mind here John 19:30
John 19:30 the Bible says when Jesus
therefore had received the vinegar he
said it is what what did he say what did
Jesus say on the cross what is the last
thing he said it is
finished and he bowed his head and gave
up the
ghost what does it mean to be finished
when something is finished what does
that mean give me another word for
finished it is finished it is what give
me another word what other words would
you use you're talking to your kids and
they're trying to argue with you for and
you say look it's finished what are you
saying what are you saying it's
complete very specific word it's
accomplished it's done
it's set it's settle it's
settle
it's I'm giving you all the hints that I
can give you and pron it is
settled it is
settled what is the ceiling it a it's a
settling into the truth what was settled
at the
cross what was settled at the cross is
that Christ died to make you a son and
daughter of God meaning the evidence
that I am a Son of God my evidence is
the cross every time the Devil Comes are
you really Son of God Point him to the
Cross why because there it was settled
but you have to
believe you have to believe that it was
settled at the cross that it was
finished at the
cross that your
salvation was determined at the cross
and it is applicable to you because you
have brought in the cross you have
accepted the cross and so there is the
it is finished point for you that's my
evidence right there listen to this
listen to
this listen to this hanging upon the
cross
hanging upon the cross Christ was the
Gospel now we have a message behold that
this is listen y'all this is manuscript
releases volume 21 and and and she's
speaking here about an end time message
here's what you hanging upon the cross
Christ was the Gospel now we have a
message Behold the Lamb of God which
taketh away the sins of the world will
not our church members keep their eyes
fixed on a crucified and Risen Savior in
whom their hopes of eternal life are
centered this is our message our
argument our Doctrine our warning to the
impenitent our encouragement for The
Sorrowing the hope for every
believer if we can awaken an interest in
men's Minds that will cause them to fix
their eyes on Christ we may step
aside and ask them only to continue to
fix their eyes upon the Lamb of of God
they thus receive their lesson whosoever
will come after me let him deny himself
and take up his cross and follow me he
who has eyes he whose Eyes Are Fixed On
Jesus will leave all he will die to
selfishness he will believe in all the
word of God which is so gloriously and
wonderfully exalted in Christ listen as
The Sinner sees Jesus as he is an all
compassionate savior hope and Assurance
take possession of his soul the helpless
soul is cast without any reservation
Upon Jesus none can bear away from the
vision of Christ Jesus crucified a
lingering doubt unbelief is gone wow wow
let me keep reading here is another
another source gospel workers 92 the
thought that the righteousness of Christ
is imputed to us not because of Any
Merit on our heart but as a free gift
from God is a precious thought the enemy
of God and man is not willing that this
truth should be clearly presented for he
knows that if the people receive it
fully his power will be
broken
wow if he can control mind so that doubt
and unbelief in darkness shall compose
the experience of those who claim to to
be the children of God he can overcome
them with temptation that simple faith
that takes God at his word should be
encouraged God's people must have faith
which will lay hold of divine power for
by grace are you saved through faith and
that not of yourselves it is the gift of
God are y'all with me
here are y'all understanding the depth
of this sealing message the holy spirit
is seeking to convince us that we are
truly Sons and Daughters of
God now you're saying but Pastor what
about the end time context what about
Revelation chapter 14 well let's go
there Revelation 14:6 this is if y'all
are not sitting down y'all need to sit
down now because y'all about to be blown
away not by me but by the spirit of God
listen to me y'all Revelation 146 the
Bible says and I saw another angel fly
in the midst of Heaven having the
Everlasting gospel to preach unto them
that dwell on on the earth and to Every
Nation Kindred tongue and people saying
with a loud voice fear God and give
glory to him for the hour of his
judgment is come and worship him that
made Heaven and Earth the sea and The
Fountains of waters
now we know beloved we know that this
first Angel's message is speaking about
the Judgment but then it culminates with
this phrase that actually comes from the
Old Testament fear God or or worship him
that made Heaven the Earth the sea and
The Fountains of waters
now where is that phrase taken from well
let me show you it's taken from Exodus
20 ver 8 onward listen to what the Bible
says remember the Sabbath day to keep it
holy six days shalt thou labor and do
all thy work but the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God in it Thou
shalt not do any work thou nor thy son
nor thy daughter thy man's servant nor
thy maid servant nor thy cattle nor thy
stranger that is within thy gates for in
six days the Lord made Heaven and Earth
the sea and all that in the midst and
rested the seventh day wherefore the
Lord blessed the Sabbath day and
hallowed it now listen to me we
understand that the the the the Sabbath
out of all the Commandments contains the
elements of a
seal a seal is going to have the
individual's name their territory and
their position of authority and the
Sabbath is the only Commandment that has
all the elements of a seal so while the
spirit of God is the one that
seals the
Sabbath
identifies who the Creator
is it is his
seal now why is this significant in
light of everything we've just been
talking about about listen to me you
guys what is the message of the
Sabbath what is the message what is the
main thing that we're not to do on
Sabbath one word y'all one word the
Sabbath is is is opposed to
what I just got to read this Samantha
thank you for putting that in the chat
several have written to me inquiring if
the message of justification by faith is
the third Angel's message and I have
replied it is the third Angel's message
in Verity yes Christie yes Michelle yes
John yes mosy yes ranne yes yes verette
yes yes yes yes the Sabbath is
100% against what
work you put a seven in the chat if you
are following this right now the Sabbath
is to remind us to not
work why is that
significant wow wow
wow it is to remind us beloved that our
works do not save us it's
already settled once we accept it by
faith the Sabbath day is designed to
teach us every week week after week to
remind us that it is not by our
works it is righteousness by faith in
Christ
Jesus
every Sabbath that rolls around is a
reminder Jesus is like look I don't want
you to do any work because I need you to
understand that you cannot save yourself
by
anything you
do so this whole day I want you to re
rest and I want that to be a
reminder that you are resting in the
completed work of Christ listen to what
Galatians 2:16 says knowing that a man
is not justified by The Works of the law
but by the faith of Jesus Christ even we
have believed in Jesus Christ that we
might be justified by the Faith of
Christ not by The Works of the law for
by The Works of the law shall no flesh
be justified the Sabbath commandment
teaching teaches us not to work it
teaches us that works listen to me it
teaches us that we are to rest in the
finished work of Christ you see you see
Exodus 31:13 tells
us speak thou unto the children of
Israel saying verily my sabbaths you
shall keep for it is a sign between me
and you that you may know that I am the
Lord that sanctified you did y'all see
that you you cannot sanctify Yourself by
your works we were literally told I need
you to keep the Sabbath so that you may
remember that I sanctify you you can't
sanctify yourself there is nothing you
no work you could possibly do to make
you right in my sight it is literally
the son sign of resting y'all didn't
catch that did y'all catch
that the
Sabbath is the message of justification
by
faith not by
works by faith
in fact you remember you remember right
Genesis 2 uh the Bible says in verse one
thus the heavens and the Earth were
finished and all the hostes of them and
on the seventh day God ended his work
which he had made and he rested on the
seventh day from all his work which he
had made and God blessed the seventh day
and Sanctified it because that in it he
had rested from all his work which God
created and made in other
words oh no no no no thus were the
heavens and the Earth
finished it was
finished and then God
Sabbath and told man Sabbath I want you
to Sabbath in the finished work of
creation Sabbath that's what Adam and
Eve did they Sabbath in the finished
work you had no part in the
creation what did you do in the creation
account to help did you deserve the rest
ah it's time for me to not sit back and
rest man it was a busy week but God and
us we we worked together man it was
hectic no no no no no you rest in what I
did you get to rest in the work that I
did the six days of creation ended with
this term it is finished what about
redemption in Redemption Christ is on
the cross saying listen y'all it is
finished not all I need you to do
Jesus after he says it is finished rests
on the
Sabbath he says I just need you to learn
how to rest in the work that I've
accomplished for you and when you learn
to rest in the work that I've
accomplished for you it is in essence
you settling
in you're now settling in to what I have
done for you relax in me Michelle says
the the spirit of God moved upon the
face of the waters that word literally
means relax relax in
me the Sabbath is the sign it is a
symbol that you have learned to rest not
in your works but in the works he did on
our
behalf it is
finished in Genesis it is finished look
at the screen check this out y'all in in
Eden it is finished it was creation at
Calvary it is finished it was Redemption
y'all need to understand that just as
the Sabbath pointed backward to the
creation account and the finished work
so in the new creation when God
recreates Us in His image the Sabbath
points to the fact that he did it we not
us he did it not us to all who will
receive the Sabbath as a sign of Christ
creative and redem and and redeeming
power creative and redeeming power it
will be a delight seeing Christ in it
they Delight themselves in him the
Sabbath points them to the works of
creation as an Evidence of his mighty
power in
Redemption while it calls to mind the
Lost piece of Eden it tells of Peace
restored through the Savior and every
object in nature repeats his invitation
come unto me all ye that labor and are
heavy laden and I will give you rest
Desire of Ages page
289 beloved this is
powerful the sealing message is a
settling into the truth that God has
called us his sons and his daughters and
we are resting in that through the
symbol of the Sabbath we are resting in
Christ by the way by the way y'all ready
for this I don't know if you'reall ready
for this I don't know if y let's let's
let's check this out let's let's go to
Isaiah
58:12 and they that shall be of thee
shall build the old waste places Thou
shalt be thou shalt raise up the
foundation of many generations Thou
shalt be called the repairer of the
breach the restorer of paths to dwell
in if you turn away your foot from the
Sabbath from doing thy pleasure on my
holy day and call the Sabbath a delight
the holy of the Lord honorable and shall
honor him not doing thine own ways
ways ways nor finding own pleasure nor
speaking thine own words ways Spirit
words
logos then shalt thou Delight thyself in
the Lord and I will cause thee to ride
upon the high places of the earth and
feed thee with the heritage heritage of
Jacob for the mouth of the Lord has
spoken and I want you to understand
beloved that when we understand the
Sabbath what it truly means to us then
is when we Delight ourselves in the Lord
because every Sabbath we are reminded
you are Son of
God we are reminded it's not by your
works we are reminded that Jesus
finished that work on the cross on our
behalf and now I get to rest in it and I
get a whole day every other day of the
week I'm working but today I just spend
the whole day meditating upon the
Beautiful ful truth that my salvation
was completed at the cross and it is
applicable to me because I have accepted
it by
faith
resting I got a little story then I got
just a few more verses and we're done
resting um how many of you can float how
many of you can
float okay I can't swim I can't float
when when when you know sometimes my my
daughters would try to teach me how to
how to just float cuz I don't have like
to me well for me I don't have any fat
on my body so I feel like I just sink to
the bottom of the water that's that's my
mentality I just sink so my my daughters
would be like Dad we got you just just
just float and I'm like just float like
no and I'm like okay let me go and see
what happens they let me go and I just I
just slowly sink to the bottom and I'm
just just looking at them as I'm going
down in the water and I'm like see I
told you
right I want you to understand
beloved I'm a sinker yeah yeah yeah some
of y'all are
sinkers in a spiritual sense God is
saying to us stop trying to
swim stop trying to
swim you're you've been in the water and
you're trying to swim and you're trying
to he says I need you to stop swimming I
just need you to float I got
you just trust me I got
you I just want you to float I I need
you to relax I need you to rest I'm
telling my daughters I can't float
they're like d you need to relax just
relax
just and there's something about human
nature that doesn't want to
relax because if we
relax are you with
me
God is trying to teach us how to float
how to rest in him how to trust him
that's what he's trying to teach us how
to do come come with me back to the
screen and I want you to note this
Matthew
11:28 the Bible says come unto me all ye
that labor and are heavy laden and I
will give you rest take my yoke upon you
and learn of me for I am meek and lowly
in heart and you shall find rest unto
your souls for my yoke is easy and my
burden is light when you're temped to
doubt the
spirit who seals us so that we cannot be
moved emotionally or intellectually is
going to keep us when you're tempted to
doubt remember no the spirit said don't
trust your emotions the spirit said look
at the text and when you look at the
text and you remember yeah I am redeemed
I am a child of God mat the joy of
Salvation is returned unto me the spirit
produces God Godly emotion why not for
the sake of just being happy but because
you have trusted in the
logos this is crucial guys because
here's what I need you to understand in
Matthew 26 and the same thing is going
to happen at the end of time in Matthew
26 the Bible says and he took with him
Jesus Took with him Peter and the two
sons of Zebedee and began to be
sorrowful and very heavy then he said on
to them my soul is
exceeding sorrowful even unto death T
you here and watch with me listen
y'all
Jesus was
emotionally sorrowful even unto
death Jesus was tempted in all points
like as we
are and Jesus Jesus in that moment in
the Garden of Gethsemane when when when
fear or when darkness began to Cloud
around him and the father's presence
began to be drawn away and he could not
sense it couldn't feel it even on the
cross I need you to understand that in
those moments Jesus had to rely not on
what he was feeling but he had to r on
the what happened back at the baptism
when the spirit of God descended and
said and and and he heard the voice this
is my beloved Son in whom I'm well
pleased in other words the faith of
Jesus is what got him through his dark
time and that's why we need the faith of
Jesus listen to this listen to this
desire Ages page 7
756 amid the awful Darkness apparently
forsaken of God Christ had drained the
last drgs in the cup of human
woe in those Dreadful hours he had
relied upon the evidence of his father's
acceptance heret for given to him that's
the baptism
y'all that's the spirit of God
testifying that Jesus was the son of
God he was acquainted with the character
of his father he understood his Justice
his mercy and his great love by faith he
rested in him whom it had ever been his
joy to obey and as in submission he
committed himself to God the sense of
the loss of his father's favor was with
was
withdrawn by faith Christ was the Victor
do y'all see that he
rested he
floated the father said son I got you
and the son said all right I'm floating
I'm floating
he
rested the Sabbath beloved is a sign
that we are resting in the finished
works of God four more verses we're done
let's go 1 John 5:4 for whatsoever is
born of God overcome the world and this
is a victory that overcome the world
even our faith our faith beloved which
is not our faith but the faith of Jesus
is what allows us to grab a hold of the
promises despite what we feel Hebrews
11:1 now Faith is the substance of
things hope for the evidence of Things
Not Seen so when the devil says man you
sure don't look like a Son of God you
point them back to the
word you point them back to the
word you point them back to the promise
of
God beloved it is this promise of God
that that that creates the
response of doing for
God we now try to live we try to live uh
uh to God's standard not because we're
trying to be saved but because he saved
us and we accepted it by faith and now
as a demonstration of my my doing right
is simply a thank
you it's the thank
you 1 John 3:2 beloved now are we the
sons of God and it does not yet appear
what we shall be but we know that when
he shall appear we shall be like him for
we shall see him as he is Faith is the
evidence substance of things hoped for
the evidence of things that have not yet
appeared we don't know what we're going
to look like as a sons of God but he
says you can claim it now you can claim
it now listen y'all closing text
Revelation 14:1 and I looked and lo a
lamb stood on the Mount
Zion and with him
144,000
having
therefore for us I don't think this
verse is even in
here so I'm going just read it
again and I looked and low a lamb stood
on Mount Zion and with him 144,000
having his father's name written in
their forehead I need y'all to
understand that the
seal that is written in the
for the father son relationship that's
why the father's name is written in
their forehead because they believe
it
I am a
Son of
God you are a son of
God despite your your your your mistakes
claim that
promise and the spirit of God is going
to begin to work Godly emotions Godly
actions Godly righteousness in your life
but it
all at the cross if you can accept that
justification by faith the power of the
enemy will be broken over you is it your
desire
to accept this truth of justification by
faith is it your desire to be sealed and
so settled into the truth that you
cannot be moved spiritually emotionally
or intellectually if that is your desire
put that seven in the chat that seven as
the symbolic number of rest Lord teach
me to float in you teach me to
rest in you have hely
father we thank you for speaking we
thank you for opening our eyes we thank
you for helping us to understand the
significance of the Sabbath as it
relates to the message of justification
by faith not justification by works Lord
please move upon us move allow the
spirit to move us so that it overrides
our sinful emotions and points us to the
logos may we hold firmly to that logos
which will in turn grant us the fruit of
the spirit love joy peace longsuffering
generous goodness Faith meekness
Temperance please Lord bless us forgive
us and may we may we reach out after you
and not let
go thank you Jesus for hearing and for
answering this prayer because we ask it
in the precious name of Jesus amen
amen
[Music]